<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:16:10 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IMDB Exploratory Analysis (Python &amp; SQL)</title>
      <link>/2021/11/imdb-exploratory-analysis-python-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:16:10 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/imdb-exploratory-analysis-python-sql/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s Lucas! I&amp;rsquo;m glad you&amp;rsquo;re here. This project is about the exploratory analysis over a cinematography databank. This was a project teached on a free course I signed called &amp;ldquo;Python Fundamentos Para Análise de Dados 3.0&amp;rdquo; from the Data Science Academy, and I enjoyed so much because it focused a lot on data munging and graph production. Thus, I saw it was important to post my step by step records, so I can come back to reuse some useful code and maybe it can teach a curious viewer 🦉.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing with Disaster Tweets</title>
      <link>/2021/11/natural-language-processing-with-disaster-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 09:04:58 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/natural-language-processing-with-disaster-tweets/</guid>
      <description>Competition Description Twitter has become an important communication channel in times of emergency. The ubiquitousness of smartphones enables people to announce an emergency they’re observing in real-time. Because of this, more agencies are interested in programatically monitoring Twitter (i.e. disaster relief organizations and news agencies).
But, it’s not always clear whether a person’s words are actually announcing a disaster.
Take this example: &amp;ldquo;Looked at the sky at night yesterday, it was ablaze&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Sales Prediction - Data Science challenge</title>
      <link>/2021/11/house-sales-prediction-data-science-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 16:50:18 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/house-sales-prediction-data-science-challenge/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna start to post my Data Science challenges, usually taken from Kaggle site.
House Rocket is a digital platform whose business model is the purchase and sale of the properties using technology. The houses have many attributes that make them more or less attractive to buyers and sellers, like numbers of bathrooms, rooms, year they were built, if/when they were reformed and other attributes. Following these informations, we can find some questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amber - Molecular Dynamics Project</title>
      <link>/2021/11/amber-molecular-dynamics-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 11:09:07 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/amber-molecular-dynamics-project/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Lucas Chitolina, and this is my first post 🌱.
I always wanted to show the scaffold of my MSc in Molecular Biology project. I worked with bioinformatics, simulating a protein behavior hipothesys on the computer through a Classic Molecular Dynamics methodology.
The objective of MD simulation is to study the dynamics of a particular system. Since we do an in silico study, we have to suit the environment of our structure as close as possible to the real system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
