<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 19:36:52 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Big Data - PySpark &amp; SQL</title>
      <link>/2021/12/big-data-pyspark-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 19:36:52 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/12/big-data-pyspark-sql/</guid>
      <description>Big Data for Data Scientists - From Mega to Giga In this post we are going to learn about the use of some tools to apply on Big Data, that differs a bit from a normal pandas-csv methodology. Working with Big Data usually demands more sophisticated software that can deal with the upload and storage of Gyga files. This was a great module I had from &amp;ldquo;Stack Academy - Big Data for Data Scientist&amp;rdquo; that, for its massive importance and content, I decided to bring to my portfolio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMDB Exploratory Analysis (Python &amp; SQL)</title>
      <link>/2021/11/imdb-exploratory-analysis-python-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:16:10 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/imdb-exploratory-analysis-python-sql/</guid>
      <description>Here’s Lucas! I’m glad you’re here. This project is about the exploratory analysis of the IMDb databank, the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular and authoritative source for movie, TV and celebrity content. This was a project taught on a free course I signed called “Python Fundamentos Para Análise de Dados 3.0” from the Data Science Academy, and I enjoyed it so much because it focused a lot on data munging and graph production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing with Disaster Tweets</title>
      <link>/2021/11/natural-language-processing-with-disaster-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 09:04:58 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/natural-language-processing-with-disaster-tweets/</guid>
      <description>Description: Twitter has become an important communication channel in times of emergency. The ubiquitousness of smartphones enables people to announce an emergency they’re observing in real-time. Because of this, more agencies are interested in programmatically monitoring Twitter (i.e. disaster relief organizations and news agencies).
But, it’s not always clear whether a person’s words are announcing a disaster.
Take this example: &amp;ldquo;Looked at the sky at night yesterday, it was ablaze&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Sales Prediction - Data Science challenge</title>
      <link>/2021/11/house-sales-prediction-data-science-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 16:50:18 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/house-sales-prediction-data-science-challenge/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna start to post my Data Science challenges, usually taken from the Kaggle site. House Rocket is a digital platform whose business model is the purchase and sale of properties using technology. The houses have many attributes that make them more or less attractive to buyers and sellers, like numbers of bathrooms, rooms, the year they were built, if/when they were reformed and other attributes. Following this information, we can find some questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amber - Molecular Dynamics Project</title>
      <link>/2021/11/amber-molecular-dynamics-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 11:09:07 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/amber-molecular-dynamics-project/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Lucas Chitolina, and this is my first post 🌱.
I always wanted to show the scaffold of my MSc in Molecular Biology project. I worked with bioinformatics, simulating a protein behavior hypothesis on the computer through a Classical Molecular Dynamics methodology.
The objective of MD simulation is to study the dynamics of a particular system. Since we do an in silico study, we have to suit the environment of our structure as close as possible to the real system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
